[Home](https://teaminternet.com/ "Home") Privacy Policy

Privacy **Policy**
==================

Our statement of use, management and disclosure of personal information.

### Welcome to our Privacy Policy

1. [Important Information and Who We Are](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#1-important-information-and-who-we-are)
    
2. [Data We Collect](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#2-data-we-collect)
    
3. [How is Your Personal Data Collected?](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#3-how-is-your-personal-data-collected)
    
4. [How We Use Your Data](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#4-how-we-use-your-data)
    
5. [Sharing of Your Data](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#5-sharing-of-your-data)
    
6. [Transfers of Data](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#6-transfers-of-data)
    
7. [Data Security](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#7-data-security)
    
8. [Data Retention](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#8-data-retention)
    
9. [Your Rights and How to Access your Data](https://teaminternet.com/privacy-policy/#9-your-rights-and-how-to-access-your-data)

#### 1\. Important Information and Who We Are

**Purpose of This Privacy Policy** 

This Privacy Policy aims to give you information on how Team Internet collects and processes your personal data through your use of this website.  

This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children. 

It is important that you read this Privacy Policy together with any other Privacy Policy or fair processing policy we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This Privacy Policy supplements other notices and privacy policies and is not intended to override them. 

**Controller**

Team Internet Group PLC  (“Team Internet”) is the company that operates the teaminternet.com website. Team Internet Group PLC is a company registered in England & Wales with Registration Number 08576358. Team Internet is a leading global internet solutions company that operates in two highly attractive markets: high-growth digital advertising (Online Marketing segment) and domain name management solutions (Online Presence segment). 

Team Internet is committed to protecting the privacy of its users our services are developed to ensure your privacy and confidentiality. 

**Data Privacy**

We take data security and data privacy seriously. If you have questions or concerns please contact us:

Email: [privacy@teaminternet.com](mailto:privacy@teaminternet.com) 

Address: Team Internet Group PLC, 4th Floor, Saddlers House, 44 Gutter Lane, London, EC2V 6BR 

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance. 

**Changes to the Privacy Policy and Your Duty to Inform Us of Changes** 

We keep our Privacy Policy under regular review. This version was last updated on 4th September 2023.  

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. 

**Third-Party Links**

Third-party partners of teaminternet.com and other websites you may access via teaminternet.com may have different policies and are not subject to this Privacy Policy. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. Team Internet recommends that you read the privacy statement of each such website you visit once you leave our website to find out how they protect your personal information. 

#### 2\. Data We Collect

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data). 

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows: 

* **Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier.
* **Contact Data** includes email address and telephone numbers.
* **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
* **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website, products and services.
* **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data could be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data will not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy. 

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences. 

#### 3\. How is Your Personal Data Collected?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through: 

**Direct Interactions****.** You may give us your data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you: 

* apply for our products or services;
* subscribe to our service or publications;
* request marketing to be sent to you;
* enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
* give us feedback or contact us.

**Automated Technologies or Interactions.** As you interact with our website, we will automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. Please see our [Cookie Policy](https://teaminternet.com/cookie-policy/) for further details. 

#### 4\. How We Use Your Data

The type of information you provide to us and how we use it depends upon how you use our services. For example information you may provide your name email and postal address when you contact us by phone, letter or using the webform contact facility on this website. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances: 

* Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
* Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
* Where we need to comply with a legal obligation.

We will only use your personal data for lawful basis. This includes: 

* **Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.
* **Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.
* **Comply with a legal obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation that we are subject to.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data although we will get your consent before sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us. 

**Purposes for Which We Will Use Your Personal Data**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate. 

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below. 

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Purpose/Activity** | **Type of data** | **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest** |
| To manage our relationship with you which will include:<br><br>(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy<br><br>(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Profile<br><br>(d) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you<br><br>(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation<br><br>(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services) |
| To enable you to complete a survey | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Profile<br><br>(d) Usage(e) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you<br><br>(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business) |
| To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Technical | (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)<br><br>(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation |
| To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Profile<br><br>(d) Usage(e) Marketing and Communications<br><br>(f) Technical | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy) |
| To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | (a) Technical<br><br>(b) Usage | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy) |
| To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Technical(<br><br>d) Usage(e) Profile<br><br>(f) Marketing and Communications | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business) |

**Marketing Communications** 

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising.  Where you or the company you represent have opted-in to receive such communications we may send you information about our products and services. You may “unsubscribe” using the link found on the bottom of such communications. 

**Cookies** 

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://teaminternet.com/cookie-policy/). 

**Change of Purpose**  

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please [contact us](https://teaminternet.com/contact/).  

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so. 

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law. 

#### 5\. Sharing of Your Data

Team Internet only shares information as described in this Privacy Policy. We require third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions. 

To the extent permitted by law, your personal data may be disclosed to the following third parties: 

* We may share your personal information with any member of our group companies affiliated with Team Internet Group PLC.
* We may share with a third party which contracts with us to provide certain of the services you have been requested.
* If we sell or buy any business or assets in which case we may disclose your data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
* If Team Internet or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party in which data including personal data associated with registrars for example will form part of the transferred assets or;
* If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation; or to protect the rights property or safety of Team Internet, or its customers.
* For support purposes, we may provide access to your personal data to providers of third-party support services. 
* Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice. 

#### 6\. Transfers of Data

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Many of our external third parties are based outside the UK and the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the UK and the EEA. 

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the UK and the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented: 

* We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.
* Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the UK and the EEA.  

#### 7\. Data Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. 

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so. 

#### 8\. Data Retention

How long do we retain your information? 

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. If we have your data because we are preforming services for you or an organisation you represent then your information will be retained for the duration of the services and for 6 years thereafter, unless otherwise agreed. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. 

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

#### 9\. Your Rights and How to Access Your Data

All information that Team Internet has collected is available online in your account and you may access such information at any time by logging in to your account. 

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data: 

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to access information we hold about you and receive information about how we process it. 

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us to protect your security and comply with our data accuracy policies. 

**Request erasure of your personal data.** You may request to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reasons for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. 

**Object to processing of your personal data** where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms. 

**Request restriction of processing of your personal data**. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in such limited circumstances as: where you wish to cancel all services and close your accounts; or where you need us to hold the data to establish, exercise or defend legal claims when we would normally delete or anonymise the data. 

**Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party.** We will allow you to copy your information held by us. If you wish to transfer domain names to another registrar please login and go to the “Manage Transfers” tab on the website. 

**Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent. 

**Automated decision-making****.** Other than the use of cookies, logs and web beacons, set out above which are automated on the website, we do not use automated profiling or decision making based upon your personal information in providing you with services. We will not contact you solely as a result of visiting our website. 

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us on privacy@teaminternet.com. 

**No fee usually required** 

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we could refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances. 

**Further Information** 

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response. 

**Time to respond** 

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
